AD.MC.012
AbuDhabi
- Group of masted ships in dock, one with the name "Helios" another in the distance with a two-word name, the second of which is "Teresa" 11.9 x 16.2 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Docks; Flags; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Ships; Turkey
- Man, sitting next to a sheep, smoking a pipe and a boy sitting on the curb of a street. Covered wheeled carts sit behind a fence with covers on them labeled "RUSTON PROCTOR LINCOLN ENGLAND" 12 x 16.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Animals; Beards; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Streets; Turkey
- Fisherman standing on a boat, pulling in a net in the foreground, three two-masted ships in the background. 12 x 16.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Boats; Fishermen; Fishing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mountains; Photographic Prints; Ships; Turkey; Water
- Two men, one in a bowler hat, talking on the street in front of a street produce market. Piles of melons are stached against the wall of a building. 12 x 16.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Fruits & Vegetables; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Men; Photographic Prints; Street Vendors; Streets; Turkey
- Five men praying on a prayer rug on the deck of a ship, one man looks directly at the camera. A lifeboat hanging in the background indicates the boat is from Liverpool. 12 x 16.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Praying; Religion; Ships; Turkey
- The Tsar Cannon on display on the grounds of the Moscow Kremlin in Russia. A small boy sits on the pedestal on which the cannon is placed. 12 x 16.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Boys; Cannons; Gelatin Silver Prints; Military / Soldiers; Moscow Kremlin; Moscow, Russia; Photographic Prints
- A man in a hat and apron sitting hunched over, working on a street. Two men sit to the left, one smoking, and another man stands to the right. 12 x 16.4 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Men; Photographic Prints; Smoking; Street Vendors; Streets; Turkey
- Man in a hat walking across a street with a cane under his left arm. In the background, men load melons onto baskets slung over a donkey's back. 12 x 16.4 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Animals; Canes & Walking Sticks; Fruits & Vegetables; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Streets; Turkey
- Tsar Bell, Moscow, Russia. A man in a uniform stands in the foreground. 16.4 x 12 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Moscow Kremlin; Moscow, Russia; Photographic Prints; Tsar Bell; Uniforms
- Portrait of a standing man with mustache and goatee wearing a high light-colored collar and a three-piece. 16.4 x 12 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Beards; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Turkey
- Mausoleum of Saladin, Damascus. 27.1 x 20.7 cm, Undated; Bonfils, Felix (Box 4)
  Archaeological Sites; Architecture; Buildings; Damascus, Syria; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mausoleum of Saladin; Photographic Prints; Tombs
- Ras Beirut seen from a cliff on the side of a harbor. 20.5 x 26.9 cm, Circa 1870; Bonfils, Felix (Box 4)
  Beirut; Boats; Buildings; Fishermen; Fishing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Lebanon; Photographic Prints; Water
- Beiteddine Palace, Lebanon. 20.5 x 27 cm, Circa 1880; Bonfils, Felix (Box 4)
  Architecture; Buildings; Fountains; Gelatin Silver Prints; Lebanon; Men; Photographic Prints
- Temple of the Sun (also called the Temple of Jupiter) in Baalbek, Lebanon. 20.5 x 27 cm, Circa 1880; Bonfils, Felix (Box 4)
  Archaeological Sites; Baalbek, Lebanon; Buildings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Temple of the Sun; Temples
- Port of Mersin, Turkey (Port de Mersina, Syria). 20.5 x 27 cm, Circa 1870; Bonfils, Felix (Box 4)
  Boats; Buildings; Docks; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mersin, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Ports; Ships; Water
- Building interior with furnishings. In the foreground stands a couch, round table and four upholstered spindle-back chairs. 35 x 27.8 cm, Undated; Bonfils, Felix (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Albumen Prints; Architecture; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Vases
- Columns of the Temple of the Sun (also called the Temple of Jupiter) and surrounding ruins in Baalbek, Lebanon. 27.8 x 35.1 cm, Undated; Bonfils, Felix (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites; Baalbek, Lebanon; Photographic Prints; Temple of the Sun; Temples
- Man with a mustache standing with his right arm on a column in a long, dark jacket, light vest and shirt, a dark bow tie and a ring on his right little finger. 10.5 x 6.2 cm, Undated; Bonfils, Felix (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Albumen Prints; Beirut; Bow Ties; Carpets; Jewellery; Men; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Syria
- Woman wearing a light colored lace-trimmed top. 41.4 x 34.3 cm, 25 [...?] 1916; Samanci, Asil; Studio Photo Apollon (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Albumen Prints; Constantinople; Formal Dress; Greek Writing; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
- Woman with a crescent shaped hair ornament. 43 x 35 cm, 1910; Samanci, Asil; Studio Photo Apollon (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Albumen Prints; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Jewellery; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
- Tomb of Sultan Murad II in the Muradiye Complex, Bursa, Turkey. The tomb sits on a stone pedestal and exposed soil can be seen on the surface of the tomb. 31.6 x 35.5 cm, Undated; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Albumen Prints; Bursa, Turkey; Muradiye Complex; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Tombs
- Gate of the Sultan at Dolmabahce Palace, Istanbul, Turkey. 31.8 x 36.8 cm, Undated; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Albumen Prints; Architecture; Dolmabahce Palace, Istanbul, Turkey; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints
- The Great Mabeyn Pavilion at Yildiz Palace, Istanbul, Turkey. 31.7 x 34.4 cm, Undated; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Albumen Prints; Architecture; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Windows; Yildiz Palace, Istanbul, Turkey
- Fountain on a street with the Aziziye Mosque in the background. 31.8 x 36.4 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Albumen Prints; Aziziye Mosque; Fountains; Horses; Konya, Turkey; Men; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Street Vendors; Trees
- Sultan Ahmed Mosque (The Blue Mosque) Istanbul, Turkey. 32 x 42.6 cm, Undated; Sebah, Pascal (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Albumen Prints; Blue Mosque, Istanbul, Turkey; Istanbul, Turkey; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Trees
- Ablution fountain in the courtyard of Selimiye Mosque in Edirne, Turkey. A group of men gather around the fountain, looking toward the camera. French writing on front. 29.9 x 43 cm, 1894; Sebah, Pascal (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Albumen Prints; Architecture; Edirne, Turkey; Fountains; French Writing; Men; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Selimiye Mosque
- Dolmabahce Mosque with ships sailing in the Bosphorus in the background. 32.1 x 43.3 cm, Undated; Studio Photographie Parisienne (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Albumen Prints; Architecture; Bosphorous, Istanbul, Turkey; Dolmabahce Mosque; Istanbul, Turkey; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Ships
- Family portrait. 32.8 x 40 cm, 1930; Sebah & Joaillier, Pera, Constantinople (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Albumen Prints; Constantinople; Family Portraits; Furnishings; Girls; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
- Ramla, the Tower of the 40 Martyrs (the White Tower). 20.3 x 25.7 cm, 1865; Studio Dumas Photagraphe a Beyrout, Lebanon (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites; Architecture; Churches; Men; Photographic Prints; Ramla; Religious Sites; White Mosque, Ramla
- Panorama of the city of Ramla with a graveyard in the foreground. 20.6 x 26.9 cm, Circa 1870; Studio Dumas Photagraphe a Beyrout, Lebanon (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Albumen Prints; Buildings; Cemeteries; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Ramla; Tombs; Trees
- Pine forest, Beirut. 20.3 x 26.9 cm, Undated; Studio Dumas Photagraphe a Beyrout, Lebanon (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Albumen Prints; Beirut; Camels; Children; Men; Parks; Photographic Prints; Roads; Trees
- "Portrait of two Mahometan Women," one standing, one sitting with a drum, dressed as an odalisque and servant. 26.9 x 20.4 cm, Circa 1893; Comtesse de Croix-Mesnil; Studio Dumas Photagraphe a Beyrout, Lebanon (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Albumen Prints; Carpets; Furnishings; Jewellery; Musical Instruments; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Traditional Dress; Turkey; Vases; Women
- Woman wearing a light veil. 35.1 x 27.8 cm, Undated; Comtesse de Croix-Mesnil; Studio Dumas Photagraphe a Beyrout, Lebanon (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Albumen Prints; Jewellery; Musical Instruments; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Veils; Women
- Two women in traditional dress, one standing holding a tambourine, one holding the hose of a shisha pipe. 35 x 27.8 cm, Circa 1870; Comtesse de Croix-Mesnil; Studio Dumas Photagraphe a Beyrout, Lebanon (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Albumen Prints; Carpets; Furnishings; Musical Instruments; Nargiles; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Smoking; Studio Photography; Traditional Dress; Veils; Women
- Two tents in the Forest of the Cedars of God in the Kadisha Valley in Lebanon. 27.8 x 35 cm, Circa 1870; Studio Dumas Photagraphe a Beyrout, Lebanon (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Albumen Prints; Forest of the Cedars of God; Kadisha Valley; Lebanon; Nature; Photographic Prints; Trees
- Still-life of a cedar branch and cones with some stones at the bottom. Taken on Mount Lebanon. 35 x 27.8 cm, Undated; Studio Dumas Photagraphe a Beyrout, Lebanon (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Albumen Prints; Forest of the Cedars of God; Lebanon; Mount Lebanon; Nature; Photographic Prints; Trees
- Tekkiye Mosque (Sultan Selim Mosque) on the banks of the Barada River in Damascus. 27.8 x 35 cm, Undated; Studio Dumas Photagraphe a Beyrout, Lebanon (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Albumen Prints; Barada River; Damascus, Syria; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Rivers; Tekkiye Mosque
- First Lieutenant Mahmud Nedim with dozens of soldiers standing on a battlefield in military uniforms and fezes. 26.8 x 33 cm, 24 August 1907; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Cannons; Fezes / Tarbouches; Guns; Military / Soldiers; Officers; Ottoman Writing; Swords & Knives; Trees; Turkey; Turkish Writing; Uniforms; Wars
- First Lieutenant Mahmud Nedim. 26.8 x 33 cm, 24 August 1907; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Albumen Prints; Cannons; Fezes / Tarbouches; Guns; Military / Soldiers; Officers; Photographic Prints; Swords & Knives; Trees; Turkey; Turkish Writing; Uniforms; Wars
- Group photo of soldiers with mustaches, some with beards, wearing military uniforms and fezes. 27 x 32.3 cm, Undated; Donatosian, Z.G. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Albumen Prints; Baghdad, Iraq; Beards; Carpets; Fezes / Tarbouches; Men; Military / Soldiers; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Swords & Knives; Uniforms
- Group photo of uniformed soldiers with mustaches wearing fezes, many of whom are holding swords. In the background, a line of men stand on a terrace overhead. 26.7 x 32.5, Undated; Studio Photographie Parisienne (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Albumen Prints; Baghdad, Iraq; Fezes / Tarbouches; Military / Soldiers; Mustaches; Officers; Swords & Knives; Uniforms
- Entrance to Yedikule Fortress, with a man in dark clothing and a fez standing in the foreground on an approaching dirt road. 27.1 x 33.1 cm, Undated; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Albumen Prints; Buildings; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Photographic Prints; Trees; Yedikule Fortress, Istanbul, Turkey
- Selimiye Mosque on the left and the Old Mosque of Edirne on the right. In the middle ground, carts with barrels and people are pulled by oxen and in the foreground, a boy sits smiling, looking at the camera. 23.6 x 30.2 cm, 1890; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Albumen Prints; Animals; Boys; Buildings; Edirne, Turkey; French Writing; Men; Mosques; Old Mosque, Edirne; Photographic Prints; Selimiye Mosque
- Arab girl wearing a veil, looking to her left, wearing an intricate metal necklace and holding her left hand to her chest. On reverse side of ref274. 29.9 x 23.6 cm., Undated; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Albumen Prints; Egypt; Girls; Jewellery; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Veils
- Two veiled women, carrying water pots on their heads, and a child seated on the ground in between them. On reverse side of ref273. 29.9 x 23.6 cm., Undated; Sebah, Pascal (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Albumen Prints; Egypt; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Pottery; Traditional Dress; Turkey; Veils; Women
- Portrait of a couple. Woman wearing a veil and man wearing a military cap and moustache. 29.3 x 19.6 cm., Undated; Sebah & Joaillier, Pera, Constantinople (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Albumen Prints; Boots; Couples; Military / Soldiers; Mustaches; Ottoman Clothing; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Uniforms; Veils
- First Lieutenant Ismail Hakki angled to his left, wearing a suit, tie, striped white shirt and moustache. 25.9 x 20.3 cm., Undated; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Mustaches; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Turkey; Turkish Writing
- Man with small toothbrush moustache, wearing a three-piece suit and plaid tie. 29.6 x 19.5 cm., Undated; Studio Paul Tarkoul (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Turkey
- 43 girls from Zapyon Greek High School, seated and standing around two long tables. 24.9 x 32.8 cm., 1912; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Albumen Prints; Furnishings; Girls; Greek Writing; Groups, Social; Photographic Prints; Turkey
- Bosphorus. View from the Asian shore towards the opposite European shoe with the Rumelihisari Castle across the water. 25.9 x 33.4 cm, Circa 1870; Sebah, Pascal (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Albumen Prints; Architecture; Boats; Bosphorous, Istanbul, Turkey; Buildings; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Roumeli Hissar Castle
- Group of people standing in front of a mosque in Adapazari. An imam stands in front of the group leading the prayer. 25 x 33 cm, Circa 1890; Studio Pantoykian (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Adapazari, Turkey; Albumen Prints; Armenian Writing; Greek Writing; Groups, Social; Mosques; Photographic Prints
- Yedikule Fortress in Constantinople with grass in the foreground and a house in front of the fort. 27 x 33.1 cm., Undated; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Albumen Prints; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Yedikule Fortress, Istanbul, Turkey
- Walls and battlements of the Yedikule Fortress, with patches of grass in front. 27.1 x 33.2 cm., Undated; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Bird's eye view of Bursa. 26.6 x 35 cm., Circa 1870; Sebah, Pascal (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Albumen Prints; Buildings; Bursa, Turkey; Houses; Landscapes; Mountains; Photographic Prints
- Walls of Constantinople. 27.2 x 33 cm., Undated; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Constantinople; Gelatin Silver Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Yedikule Fortress, Istanbul, Turkey
- Three men in front of the Fountain of Sultan Ahmed III in the square outside the Topkapi Palace. 34 x 26 cm., 1860; Sebah, Pascal (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Albumen Prints; Arabic Calligraphy; Architecture; Fountain of Sultan Ahmed III; Fountains; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Nargiles; Photographic Prints; Smoking; Streets; Topkapi Palace
- Man in traditional dress firing a gun from the banks of the Jordan River. 21.7 x 27.8 cm, Circa 1910; American Colony, Jerusalem (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Albumen Prints; Guns; Jerusalem; Jordan River; Nature; Photographic Prints; Rivers; Traditional Dress; Trees
- The Jordan River with a man standing in a rowboat on the bank. 28 x 35.7 cm, Circa 1910; American Colony, Jerusalem (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Albumen Prints; Boats; Jordan; Jordan River; Men; Nature; Photographic Prints; Rivers
- Man in traditional dress standing on the banks of the Jordan river. 27.8 x 35.8 cm, Circa 1910; American Colony, Jerusalem (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Albumen Prints; Canes & Walking Sticks; Dead Sea; Guns; Horses; Jordan; Jordan River; Nature; Photographic Prints; Rivers; Traditional Dress
- Man sitting by the Dead Sea with a group of branches stacked in a pyramid for a fire. 28 x 36 cm, Circa 1910; American Colony, Jerusalem (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Albumen Prints; Dead Sea; Hats; Jerusalem; Men; Photographic Prints
- View of Jericho from a distance with animals grazing in the foreground. 27.9 x 35.9 cm, Undated; American Colony, Jerusalem (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Albumen Prints; Animals; Jericho; Landscapes; Nature; Photographic Prints
- View of a river at the bottom of a rocky valley with a stone walkway built on the bank, a stone bridge in the middle-distance and a road built to the right. 27.8 x 35.1 cm, Undated; American Colony, Jerusalem (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Albumen Prints; Bridges; Nature; Photographic Prints; Rivers; Roads; Turkey
- Egyptian woman wearing a hijab and niqab. 35.5 x 27.9 cm, Circa 1895; Sebah, Pascal (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Albumen Prints; Egypt; Hijab (Islamic clothing); Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Traditional Dress; Women
- Fountain of Sultan Ahmed III in the square outside the Topaki Palace. On reverse side of ref294. 30.3 x 40.5 cm, Undated; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Albumen Prints; Architecture; Fountain of Sultan Ahmed III; Fountains; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Topkapi Palace
- Tomb of Sultan Mahmud II. On reverse side of ref293. 30.3 x 40.5 cm, Undated; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Albumen Prints; Buildings; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Photographic Prints; Tomb of Sultan Mahmud II; Tombs
- Entrance to Yedikule Fortress with a few men sitting outside the gate smoking shisha. 29 x 38 cm, Circa 1860; Sebah, Pascal (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Albumen Prints; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Nargiles; Photographic Prints; Smoking; Trees; Yedikule Fortress, Istanbul, Turkey
- Suleymaniye Mosque as seen from the Beyazit Tower. 28.5 x 36.8 cm, Circa 1880; Sebah, Pascal (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Albumen Prints; Bosphorous, Istanbul, Turkey; Istanbul, Turkey; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Suleymaniye Mosque
- Gate to Kucuksu Palace. On the reverse side of ref298. 27.4 x 36 cm, Circa 1870; Sebah, Pascal (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Albumen Prints; Architecture; Guns; Istanbul, Turkey; Kucuksu Palace; Photographic Prints; Windows
- Interior of the Hagia Sophia, Istanbul, Turkey. On the reverse side of ref297. 27.4 x 36 cm, Circa 1870; Sebah, Pascal (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Albumen Prints; Arabic Calligraphy; Architecture; Hagia Sophia; History; Mosques; Museums; Photographic Prints; Windows
- View of the Dome of the Rock over the Al-Aqasa Mosque on the Temple Mount, Jerusalem. Turkish writing on the back. 30.3 x 40.5 cm, Undated; Bonfils, Felix (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Albumen Prints; Buildings; Dome of the Rock; Jerusalem; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites
- Arial view of Bursa, Turkey with the Grand Mosque of Bursa (Ulucami) on the right. 30.6 x 40 cm, 1870; Sebah, Pascal (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Albumen Prints; Buildings; Bursa, Turkey; Grand Mosque of Bursa; Mountains; Photographic Prints
- Group photo of Ottoman soldiers in military uniforms holding gloves and swords. Addressing Sehzade Nurettin Efendi (1901-1944, son of Abdulhamit II) with the signature of Mulazim-i sani (second lieutenant) Nureddin (Nureddin Ibrahim Konyar, 1873 - 1932)." 27.8 x 38 cm, Undated; Studio August Toke (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Albumen Prints; Bruck, Austria; Gloves; Group Portraits; Men; Military / Soldiers; Officers; Photographic Prints; Swords & Knives; Uniforms
- Ironclad German ship flying the German Empire flag docked in Port Said, Egypt. 27.8 x 35.1 cm, Ca. 1870; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Albumen Prints; Germans; Lighthouses; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Port Said, Egypt; Ports; Ships
- Statue of Ibrahim Pasha in Cairo, Egypt. 35.8 x 28 cm, Undated; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Albumen Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Ibrahim Pasha; Men; Photographic Prints; Statues
- Egyptian woman looking off to the right in a hijab and an ornamented veil. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Albumen Prints; Jewellery; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Veils; Women
- Al Sayeda Zeinab Mosque in Cairo, Egypt. 27.7 x 21.3 cm, Undated; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Al Sayeda Zeinab Mosque; Albumen Prints; Animals; Cairo, Egypt; Men; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Women
- On the left, an ironclad ship with three masts; on the right, two more ships, all docked in Port Said, Egypt. 20.5 x 27 cm, Undated; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Albumen Prints; Boats; Lighthouses; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Port Said, Egypt; Ships
- Woman reclining on a chair, a shisha pipe hose in hand, slippered feet resting on two stacked cushions. On a table to the right there is a teacup and saucer and a shisha pipe. On reverse side of ref308. 23.6 x 29.9 cm, Undated; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Albumen Prints; Carpets; Egypt; Furnishings; Jewellery; Nargiles; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Smoking; Studio Photography; Tea; Women
- Woman looking off to the left, wearing a sheer, light-colored veil. Her hands, each with a ring, are crossed on a railing in front of her. On reverse side of ref307. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Albumen Prints; Egypt; Jewellery; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Veils; Women
- Woman wearing a niqab, carrying a naked child on her shoulder. On reverse side of ref310. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Albumen Prints; Children; Egypt; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Veils; Women
- Arab woman holding a tarabuk, and a shisha (hookah) pipe on a small table with mother-of-pearl inlay sits to the left. On reverse side of ref309. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Albumen Prints; Egypt; Furnishings; Musical Instruments; Nargiles; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Singing; Smoking; Studio Photography; Women
- Woman in traditional dress on top of a saddled donkey. The donkey wears a adorned chain around its neck and a servant with a crop stands to the rear of the donkey. On reverse side of ref312. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Albumen Prints; Animals; Donkeys; Egypt; Jewellery; Photographic Prints; Traditional Dress; Women
- Two women, one standing, holding a two-handled pot on her head and one crouching, her left hand resting on a piece of pottery. On reverse side of ref311. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; Studio Photo Varjabedian, Zagazig, Egypt. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Albumen Prints; Doors; Egypt; Jewellery; Photographic Prints; Pottery; Women
- Smiling woman, holding her dark colored veil across her body with her right hand. On reverse side of ref314. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Albumen Prints; Egypt; Jewellery; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Veils; Women
- Woman in traditional dress with hijab and a niqab. The woman carries a naked child on her left shoulder, the child's head resting on hers. On reverse side of ref313. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; Studio Photo Varjabedian, Zagazig, Egypt. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Albumen Prints; Children; Egypt; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Traditional Dress; Women
- Woman with flowers in her hair in a long light-colored dress with floral embroidery. 29.4 x 19.5 cm, Undated; Studio Photo Abel, Constantinople (Box 5, Folder 9)